Guide to the Postcards of female and male impersonators and cross-dressing, circa 1900-1930.
Postcards of female and male impersonators and cross-dressing,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Postcards of female and male impersonators and cross-dressing, circa 1900-1930.
7778
Gerard, Koskovich
380 items.
Postcards, Photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Postcards portraying cross-dressing and female and male impersonators in France, Sweden, Austria, Spain, Belgium, the United Kingdom, the United States, Germany, Italy, and Romania. Postcards include photographic and photomechanical prints, some hand-colored. All are printed between circa 1900 and 1930 and depict performers on amateur, café-concert, music-hall, and legitimate stages at the high-point of cross-dressing as a form of entertainment. Many depict gallant visual narratives of women being wooed by other women dressed as men. Additional postcards include humorous images, popular genre narratives, promotional portraits of theatrical and music-hall male and female impersonators, as well as World War I POW camp theatrical productions. Two postcards are credited to female photographers, Ilse Magenmiller (German) and Jessie Westbrook (American). Sets of postcards depict narrative sequences, including Joan of Arc, Les Cerises, Chasé-croisé, Idylle à Trianon, and Une Amourette Louis XV. One such sequence, Pierrot et Columbine (circa 1900), portrays a sexual ending with Columbine represented nude (in a pink body suit). Male and female impersonators featured include Robert Bertin, Jeanne Bloch, Leopoldo Fregoli, Monte Verdi, Louis Vernassier, Sarah Bernhardt, Gaby Deslys, John Graffton, Betti Kuhn, Hetty King, Zena Dare, Vesta Tilley, Winifred Ward, and Huntley Wright, among others.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Postcards portraying cross-dressing and female and male impersonators in France, Sweden, Austria, Spain, Belgium, the United Kingdom, the United States, Germany, Italy, and Romania. Postcards include photographic and photomechanical prints, some hand-colored. All are printed between circa 1900 and 1930 and depict performers on amateur, café-concert, music-hall, and legitimate stages at the high-point of cross-dressing as a form of entertainment. Many depict gallant visual narratives of women being wooed by other women dressed as men. Additional postcards include humorous images, popular genre narratives, promotional portraits of theatrical and music-hall male and female impersonators, as well as World War I POW camp theatrical productions. Two postcards are credited to female photographers, Ilse Magenmiller (German) and Jessie Westbrook (American). Sets of postcards depict narrative sequences, including Joan of Arc, Les Cerises, Chasé-croisé, Idylle à Trianon, and Une Amourette Louis XV. One such sequence, Pierrot et Columbine (circa 1900), portrays a sexual ending with Columbine represented nude (in a pink body suit). Male and female impersonators featured include Robert Bertin, Jeanne Bloch, Leopoldo Fregoli, Monte Verdi, Louis Vernassier, Sarah Bernhardt, Gaby Deslys, John Graffton, Betti Kuhn, Hetty King, Zena Dare, Vesta Tilley, Winifred Ward, and Huntley Wright, among others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Koskovich, Gerard,; Bertin, Robert.; Bloch, Jeanne.; Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923; Joan, of Arc, Saint, 1412-1431; Bertin, Robert; Bloch, Jeanne
Subjects:
Gender identity -- Europe; Music-halls (Variety-theaters, cabarets, etc.) -- Europe.; Sex in popular culture -- Europe; Lesbian couples -- Europe; Courtship -- Europe; Theater -- Europe; Transvestism -- Europe; Transvestites -- Europe.; Breeches parts -- Europe.; Male impersonators; Female impersonators; Women peasants -- Europe.; Cross-dressers; Manners and customs; Music-halls (Variety-theaters, cabarets, etc.); Sex in popular culture; Theater; Cross-dressing; Cross-dressers
Places:
Austria.; Belgium.; Europe.; France.; Germany.; Great Britain.; Italy.; Spain.; Romania.; United States.; France
Form and Genre Terms:
Postcards.; Gelatin silver prints; Collotypes (prints); Relief halftones (prints)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
"Female impersonator" means the individual doing the impersonating is male and "male impersonator" means the individual doing the impersonating is female.
SERIES LIST
Series I. France
Series II. Sweden
Series III. Austria
Series IV. Belgium
Series V. Spain
Series VI. United Kingdom
Series VII. Germany
Series VIII. United States
Series IX. Italy
Series X. Romania
CONTAINER LIST
- France, 1900-1925 (Box 1)
  France
  - Music Hall, Theater and Film (Box 1)
    - Albertin celebre imitateur, 1910; 1; 14.2 x 9.3 cm; Blank verso. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Albertin
      Female impersonators
      Relief halftones (prints)
    - Arigon - Imitateur, 1910; 2; 14 x 9.2 cm; Full color. Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Arigon
    - Poilu's-Park, La Grande Divette, 1915; 3; Lavaux, V.; Luce; 14 x 9.2 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      French World War I soldier posed outdoors wearing a female gypsy costume. Black rubber-stamp impression on verso: "Collection J.F.M.
      Bert-Gyll
      Collotypes (prints)
    - Poilu's-Park, Les Poilus Bert-Gyll et Mezy duettistes a transformations, 1915; 4; Lavaux, V.; Luce; 14 x 9.1 cm; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Costumes de la Maison Granier. The two cards offered here represent Poilu's Park, an amusement park for French and allied soldiers that operated from 1915 to 1916 in Commercy.
    - Bertin - Imitant la Tortojada, 1907; 5; 14 x 9.1 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Bertin, Robert
      Gelatin silver prints
    - Monsieur R. Bertin - Imitant Miss Clotilde Alegria, tireuse mexicaine, 1907; 6; 14.4 x 9.2 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Monsieur R. Bertin dans son Imitation de Miette, 1900; 7; 13.9 x 9 cm; Applied color (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Monsieur R. Bertin - Imitant Yvette Guilbert, 1907; 8; 14.3 x 9.2 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Photographer's name partially legible (reproduction of embossing on original photo). Notice printed full width indicating "Certains les pays étrangers n'acceptant pas la correspondance au recto se renseigner à la Poste.”
    - Mr Bertin - Imitation de Yvette Guilbert, 1907; 9; Bioletto, J.; 14.3 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Lyon, France
    - Mr. Bertin - Imitation de Mlle Foscolo exentrique, 1907; 10; Bioletto, J.; 14.3 x 9 cm (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mr Bertin - Imitation de Mme Yvette Guilbert genre Pompadour, 1907; 11; Bioletto, J.; 14.3 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mr. Bertin - Imitation de la Belle Otero, 1907; 12; Bioletto, J.; 14.3 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Monsieur R. Bertin dans son Imitation de l'Excentrique "Polaire", 1904; 13; 14 x 9.2 cm; Applied color. Undivided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Monsieur R. Bertin - Imitant "La Tortojada", 1904; 14; 14.1 x 9 cm; Applied color. Undivided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mr. Bertin, 1910; 15; Espiugas, A.; 13.7 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Barcelona, Spain
    - Jeanne Bloch, 1910; 16; Buger et Bert; 13.9 x 8.8 cm; Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      A comic actress who played both female and male roles in music-hall revues; dressed as a portly, gray-haired, bearded gentleman looking like then President of the French Republic, Armand Fallières. Card No. 308.
      Bloch, Jeanne
      Paris, France
      Male impersonators
    - M. Defreyn (Sarah Yacco), 1903; 17; Dupont, G.; Le Carnet Mondain; 13.8 x 9; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      An operetta star who later developed a recording and film career. In the postcard offered here, Defreyn imitates Sadda Yacco (Kawakami Sadayakko; 1871-1946), a Japanese kabuki artist who performed to audiences in Paris at the turn of the 20th century.
      Defreyn, Henri, 1878-1948
    - Mr D'Hernonville, 1904; 18; 14 x 9.1 cm; Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      A noted music-hall performer who portrayed a series of female singing and speaking roles.
      D'Hernonville
    - Mr. D'Hernonville imitateur, 1904; 19; Guilleminot, R.; Boespflug et Cie; 14 x 9.1 cm; Divided verso (Box 1, Folder 3)
      On verso: Logo of a bridled horse head framed in a horseshoe.
    - Yvette Dolly, 1924; 20; 14 x 9.1 cm; Toned. Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Inscription: Moulin Rouge Paris 27/11/24 / A Myriam mon / bon souvenir / Dolly. Black rubber-stamp impression on verso: Collection J.F.M.
      Dolly, Yvette
    - Florin Imitateur, 1910; 21; Martin, Louis; 14 x 9 cm; Divided verso (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Florin
    - Florin Imitateur, 1910; 22; Martin, Louis; 14 x 9 cm; Divided verso (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Florin Imitateur, 1910; 23; Martin, Louis; 14 x 9 cm; Divided verso (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Fregoli nella Mimi, 1902; 24; Garzinie e Pezzini; 9.1 x 13.5 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
      An internationally renowned Italian quick-change artist, Fregoli both sang and acted 20 or more characters in each of his shows. He made his first splash on the Parisian stage in 1900 and subsequently presented shows in the French capital that ran for up to a year. This card presents vignettes showing poses and costumes from Fregoli's show Mimi.
      Fregoli, Leopoldo, 1867-1936
      Milan, Italy
    - Fregoli nell Eldorado, 1902; 25; Garzinie e Pezzini; 9.1 x 14.1 cm (Box 1, Folder 3)
      An internationally renowned Italian quick-change artist, Fregoli both sang and acted 20 or more characters in each of his shows. He made his first splash on the Parisian stage in 1900 and subsequently presented shows in the French capital that ran for up to a year. This card presents vignettes showing poses and costumes from Fregoli's show Eldorado.
    - Cricket on the Hearth, 1910; 26; 8.8 x 13.8 cm; Toned. Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Based on the indication of the roles noted on the verso, the actors are appearing in a play based on the Charles Dickens novella The Cricket on the Hearth.On verso: Logo of a bridled horse head framed in a horse­shoe. Pale blue rubber-stamp impression on verso giving name and city of publisher.
      Melun, France
    - Marthis??, 1910; 27; Martin, Louis; 14 x 9 cm (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Marthis
    - Maurice homme protee, 1907; 28; 14.1 x 9.3 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Maurice
    - Maurice l'homme protee, 1910; 29; 14 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Marseille, France
    - Novelty's imitateur a transformations, 1915; 30; 14 x 9.1 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Full length photo of a man in showgirl dress; vignette headshot of same performer in white tie.
    - M. de Sternac dans son imitation de Mme Yvette Guilbert, 1907; 31; Le Ray, Cliché; Imprimeries Reunies; 14.2 x 9.1 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Sternac, Fernand de
      Nancy, France
    - M. de Sternac dans son imitation de Mme Sada Yacco, 1907; 32; Le Ray, Cliché; Imprimeries Reunies; 14.1 x 9 cm; Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Monte Verdi, 1920; 33; Boisdon, Maurice; 14 x 9 cm; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Photographer Maurice Boisdon specialized in theatrical and circus performers, cityscapes and landscapes.
      Verdi, Monte
    - Monte Verdi, 1920; 34; Boisdon, Maurice; 14 x 9 cm; Toned. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Inscription: Du 18e au 20e Siecle.
    - Louis Vernassier, l'homme protée musical dans son Travesti-dame, 1900; 35; Reutlinger; 14.1 x 9.1 cm; Undivided verso. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Vernassier, Louis
    - Louis Vernassier, l'homme protée musical excentrique dans son travesti-dame jouant, 1907; 36; 14.2 x 9.2 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Louis Vernassier protée musical excentrique dans son travesti-dame, 1910; 37; 9.2 x 14 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Inscription: Written in black ink: Mes remerciements. Black rubber-stamp impression of signature: Vernassier L. Paired portaits of Vernassier in men's clothing and in costume as grand dame. Rubber stamp on verso: "Collection J.F.M. Inscribed.
    - Couple with fan and top hat, 1900; 81; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color (Box 1, Folder 10)
      A promotional photo for a music-hall act. The only postcard in the collection that features performers of color. Publisher's monogram on recto.
    - M.R. Bertin - Le Celebre Imitateur Francais, 1907; 84; Bauer Marchet et Cie; 14 x 9 cm; Varnished. Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Publisher's name indicated in circular black rubberstamp impression on recto.
      Dijon, France
    - Bertin, 1900; 85; 14.2 x 9 cm; Applied color. Undivided verso. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - M.R. Bertin - Imitation de Mme Yvette Guilbert, 1907; 86; Bauer Marchet et Cie; 14.2 x 9 cm; Varnished. Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - M.R. Bertin - Imitation de Mlle Lydia, 1907; 87; Bauer Marchet et Cie; 14.2 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - M.R. Bertin - Imitation de Mme Ouvrard, 1907; 88; Bauer Marchet et Cie; 14.3 x 9.3 cm; Varnished. Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Monsieur (et non Mademoiselle!) Thon Lind, 1927; 89; Alferocca; 14 x 9 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Stamped and mailed in France.
      Lind, Thon
      Terni, Italy
    - M. Pol Simon - dans ses repaides transformations, 1904; 90; Imp. M. Massenet; 14.1 x 9.1 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Simon, Pol
      Chatillon, France
    - La Tolosa, 1910; 91; 14.1 x 9.6 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      La Tolosa
    - Louis Vernassier - l'homme protee musical excentrique dans ses Travesti-Dame, 1910; 92; 9.2 x 14 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Montage of three portraits of Vernassier showing his transformation from middle-aged man to grand dame.
    - Louis Vernassier - l'homme protee musical dans son Travesti Dame, 1905; 93; Riviere, R.; 14 x 9.1 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Vernassier was a popular music-hall performer.
      Angers, France
    - Louis Vernassier - l'homme protee musical dans son Travesti Dame, 1910; 94; Riviere, R.; 14 x 9.1 cm; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Louis Vernassier had a long and prolific career as a music-hall female impersonator whose act involved playing numerous musical instruments (this postcard lists 12 different ones, plus "tous les instruments excentriques").
    - L'Aiglon - Mme Sarah Bernhardt - Scene de Wagram, 1902; 95; 14.1 x 9.1 cm; Undivided verso. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Inscription: Addressed to Mlle Marguerite Beaujean. Black-and-white reproduction of a watercolor illustration signed Espinasse. Sarah Bernhardt appearing in one of her most celebrated trouser roles as the son of Napoleon in La Aiglon (1900) by playwright Edmond Rostand, who wrote the role for her.
      Bernhardt, Sarah, 1844-1923
    - Jeanne Bloch, dans Armand' retour de Londres, 1910; 96; 14.6 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Comic actor and singer Jeanne Bloch dressed as a portly, bearded man wearing a top hat and carrying a cane. Inscription at upper left on the recto indicates that Bloch was appearing at La Scala, a music hall in Paris open from 1874 to 1936.
    - Odeon - Clara Faurens, 1905; 97; 14.1 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Stage and silent-film actor Clara Faurens appearing at the Theatre de la'Odeon (Paris) in the role of Pierrot, the commedia della arte stock figure of the lovesick clown. Inscribed verso: Brief note to Jeanne Gorno signed E. Hacquet.
      Faurens, Clara
      - Chavarny, 1904; 98; 14.3 x 9.2 cm; Applied color (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Performer dressed as an 18th-century male aristocrat in a beribboned outfit and an enormous feathered cavalier hat. Inscription at upper left on the photo indicates that Mlle. Chavarny appeared at La Scala, a music hall in the 10th arrondissement of Paris open from 1874 to 1936 where many of the grand stars of the era appeared. Addressed to Isabelle Garon; signature of sender illegible.
        Chavarney
      - Declos Gaity, 1903; 99; 14.2 x 9.1 cm; Applied color (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Inscription: "Addressed to Clara (?) Boissier. inscription at upper right on the recto indicates that Mlle. Declos and Mlle. Gaity appeared at La Cigale, a music hall on the Place Pigalle in Paris that opened in 1887.
        Declos and Gaity
      - Defrance, 1904; 100; 14.2 x 9.3 cm; Applied color (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Inscription: "Addressed to Isabelle Garon; signature of sender illegible." Performer dressed as an 18th-century male aristocrat. Inscription at upper left on the photo indicates that Mlle. Defrance appeared at La Scala, a music hall in the 10th arrondissement of Paris open from 1874 to 1936 where many of the grand stars of the era appeared.
        Defrance
      - Theatre des Varietes. Barbe Bleue, 1900; 101; Paul Boyer; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Addressed to Rose Bounias; brief message on recto signed P. Paul. Actress dressed as a 17th-century cavalier, likely in the role of one of the brothers in a production of Jacques Offenbach's opera-bouffe Barbe-Bleue (1866).
        Mlle Noray
      - Liseron Parisiana, 1915; 102; 14.2 x 9.1 cm; Applied color (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Liseron
    - Sarah Bernhardt, 1902; 214; 14 x 9 cm; Inscribed. Undivided verso. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Bernhardt as the son of Napoleon in L'Aiglon. Undivided verso. Publisher initials S.I.P. on recto.
    - Sarah Bernhardt, 1904; 215; 14 x 9 cm; Inscribed. Undivided verso. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sarah Bernhardt, 1904; 216; 14 x 9 cm; Inscribed. Undivided verso. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sarah Bernhardt dans L'Aiglon, 1900; 217; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Divided verso.
    - Sarah Bernhardt, 1905; 218; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color. Inscribed. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Sarah Bernhardt dans L'Aiglon, 1903; 219; Boyer et Bert; 14 x 9 cm; Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - de Brives (Varietes), 1905; 220; Cautin et Berger; 14 x 9 cm; Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      De Brives, Gabrielle, 1883-1974
    - Theatre Marigny - Deslys, 1905; 221; Walery; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Gaby Deslys wearing the costume of a 17th-century male aristocrat.
      Deslys, Gaby, 1881-1920
    - Miss Gaby Deslys, 1915; 222; Record Press; J. Beagels and Co., Ltd.; 14 x 9 cm; Signed. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Gaby Deslys dressed in men's evening wear. The image was produced as a promotion for Deslys' appearing in London in Rosy Rapture, a one-act play by J.M. Barrie.
      London, England
    - Marise Fairy, 1910; 223; Walery; 14 x 9 cm; Inscribed by performer. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Marise Fairy in the role of Buster Brown from the Revue de Marigny, a music-hall show presented at the Theatre de Marigny in Paris.
      Fairy, Marise
    - The French Fregoli Emile Grandsart "Original Transformist", 1900; 224; Marteau, Ernest (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Music-hall protean performer Emile Grandsart, whose act involved costume quick-changes into both female and male characters.
      Grandsart, Emile
    - Monsieur D'Hernonville, le Merveilleux Protee Feminin, 1910; 225; 14.7 x 9.8 cm; Inscribed. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Monsieur D'Hernonville
    - Minouche, 1955; 226; Koruna, Paul; 14 x 9 cm; Divided verso. No inscription. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Studio shot of Minouche, one of the stars of Madame Arthur, a leading female-impersonation cabaret of Paris in the 1950s and 1960s. In this photograph, Minouche, who was white, impersonates a black performer in the style of Eartha Kitt.
      Minouche
    - Female impersonator carrying jug, 1910; 227; 14 x 9 cm; Signed. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Olganny
    - Zambelli et Mante, 1906; 228; Boyer, Paul; 14 x 9 cm; Inscribed. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Male impersonator and female dancer dressed in 17th-century costume.
    - Male impersonator in bowler hat and woman in dress, 1910; 229; Walery; 14 x 9 cm; Inscribed. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - A travers les coulisses, 1925; 230; Paris sur Scene; 14 x 9 cm; Divided verso. No inscription. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Female impersonator as a showgirl in her dress room.
    - Male impersonator in men's evening wear and earrings, 1929; 231; 14 x 9 cm; Inscribed. Divided verso. (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Halterstein, Lydia
      Dresden, Germany
  - Troops and POW shows, WWI (Box 2)
    - La Grande Guerre, 1915; 292; L'Abeille; 9 x 14 cm; Divided verso. Not inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Poilu's Park, 1915; 293; Lavaux, V.; Luce Editeur; 9 x 14 cm; Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Inscription includes reference to the type of performance shown on the postcard.
  - Gallant scenes (Box 1)
    - Les Soeurs Mante de l'Opera, 1907; 39; 13.9 x 8.9 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Suzanne and Blanche Mante, lead dancers for the Opera de Paris, enact a variation of an 18th-century galant scene.
      Mante, Suzanne
      Mante, Blanche
    - La Matchiche, 1908; 40-41; Stebbing; Kunzli Freres Editeurs; 14 x 9.1 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Set of two postcards portraying the De Tender sisters, both music-hall performers. Alice de Tender appeared at the Folies-Bergere, the Eldorado and the Moulin Rouge; she also appeared in silent films, including the feature La Veuve Joyeuse (1913) and a number of shorts. "La Matchiche"was a popular song debuted in a music-hall show in 1902; the painter Kees van Dongen borrowed the title for a 1904 oil representing dancers at the bal populaire Le Moulin de la Galette (collection of the Musee d'Art Moderne de Troyes).
      Tender, Fanny de
      Tender, Alice de
    - Estudiantina, 1907; 42-44; Stebbing; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Series of three postcards.
    - Amours Champetres, 1907; 45; Walery; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - On ne passe pas, 1903; 46; Kunzli Freres Editeurs; 14.2 x 9.2 cm; Applied color. Undivided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Je suis épris de toi, 1907; 47; 14.2 x 9.2 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Les Cerises, 1900; 48-57; Kunzli Freres Editeurs; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color. Undivided verso. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Set of 10 cards with photo narrative of an 18th-century seduction scene. Originally in a die-cut holder, they are now housed individually in mylar sleeves.
    - Ma belle Marquise, 1910; 58-59; 14 x 9 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Set of 2 cards with photo narrative of an 18th-century seduction scene. Series no. 1549.
    - An officer and an aristocrat, 1900; 60-63; 14.2 x 9.2 cm; Applied color. Divided verso. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Set of 4 cards with photo narrative of an 18th-century seduction scene. Series no. 525.
    - Idylle a Trianon, 1902; 64-66; Manuel, Henri (1874-1947); 14 x 9 cm; Applied color (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Same series depicted in cards 320-328.
    - Amourette Louis XV, 1905; 67-68; 14.2 x 9.1 cm; Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Set of two postcards with photo narrative of an 18th-century seduction scene. Same images in cards 147-148. Same series depicted in cards 146-150 and 310.
    - Fanluchette et Godichon, 1904; 69-78; Walery; Piprot; 14 x 9.1 cm; Applied color. Undivided verso. Inscribed. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Full set of 10 cards with photo narrative of an early 19th-century seduction scene. Postcards numbered 1-10, each with a one- to two-sentence narrative.
    - L'Abbe, les fiances, 1905; 82-83; 14 x 9 cm (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Same series depicted in cards 311-313.